Milton J. Rosas Paredes

Volcán Copahue # 25 Casa 4, Puerto Varas. Chile mjrp.ros@gmail.com +56 93414 4483

SUMMARY

About 20 years experienced and I've been the last 13 years working as a Technical Support Engineer Specialist implementing, designing and supporting highly available, resilient and trusted IT enterprise infrastructure and implementing world class softwares for critical and load intensive environments.

I love to be part of multidisciplinary teams and working on solving complex issues related with NSK and Linux/Unix systems, TCP/IP networks, data replicator systems and data bases.

On the other hand, I've participated as a Computer and Robotics Workshop Instructor at a school in the south of Chile at different educational levels, improving the digital knowledge and supporting different subjects using digital tools.

I'm fortunate to take my job as a challenge. I am restless and enjoy learning every day and facing each problem as a challenge to be solved.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Transbank S.A. February 2019 – Present

I was hired as a Base24 Engineer to be part of the specialized technical support team of the front-end authorization platform in the production environment. The most important project I've participated was the migration of the authorization platform infrastructure of the Development, QA and Production environments based on NSK Systems. In addition, we changed the infrastructure of our Hardware Security Modules as part of this Project by installing new HSM ATALLA AT1000 series. This project was exciting because we successfully maintained a 100% uptime of the service without affecting the service to our clients, setting a precedent in the company as the most successful and important project of the year 2020, because we met the deadlines, costs and expected results.

Other project I've created is the design of a high availability scheme for different issuerauthorizator endpoints of the financial industry in my country, providing reliability and resilience to the infrastructure of the chilean payment industry.

Currently I'm working on solving the need for migration of the Transaction Security Service component, because our version is entering in sunset, but we've decided to install the BASE24-eps version and consume the TSS component from our platform which is in BASE24-classic version.

Nowadays, we've already deployed this architecture in the development environment, achieving successful results with online transactions with PIN encryption, although we still need to perform terminal refresh tests in batch mode.

Me and my team are working daily on solving production environment issues that impacts our customers, making bug detection on the CSM's and continuous improvements over software components of the whole production autorizathion platform.

Marel Spa. August 2017 – January 2019

I was hired as a Field Service Software Analyst in this Icelandic company and I performed analysis, development and implementation of the Management Software for the Salmon

Processing Machinery. I was part of the Field Service team implementing the machinery and software that allows the configuration of this machinery and the extraction of the processing data of each piece of Salmon, with which analysis and production forecasts were carried out in a given period in different plants of salmon processing in the south of Chile.

This job was exciting because I was able to travel to Denmark to have a strong and solid training that allowed me to travel through the center and south of Chile, participating in the implementation of the machinery in different process plants and installing, supporting and customizing the Innova software which it is developed in C # and is a property of this company.

Santo Tomás School

May 2017 - July 2017

I was the Computer Workshop Instructor for primary and high school education, developing computer programming activities using educational programming tools at a primary level and the algorithms programming in C ++ language and educational programming in Javascript language for the high school level.

I was the Robotics Workshop Instructor in charge of developing didactic activities of robot construction for the primary level using the Robotis Dream level 1 kit by Robotis®.

I loved this project and I'm still in touch with teachers who still call me to give recommendations about my profession to students who are finishing their secondary educational level, before going to university. Someday I'd like to finish my career at the academy teaching from my own experience.

Transbank S.A.

October 2008 - May 2016

This was my first time working at Transbank as a Support Specialist in the production environment. We were only 3 people counting my boss when we built the Team in the last months of 2010. We received the BASE24 platform very outside of the ACI standards, so it was a great challenge to turn it into the strong, reliable and resilient platform that it is today.

Before starting the operation of the Specialized front-end Support Team, I worked as a Support Engineer for the entire transaction processing chain of the company, detecting bugs, correcting them at the moment and allowing the continuity of the operation. I participated in important projects such as, the implementation of the Workload Automation and Scheduling System (CA Workload Automation) that enables the automatic execution of the company's back-end processes.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- I love to check code for bugs when a problem occurs and stops the operation, I'm trained to do this with both imperative and declarative programming code. I've had experience reviewing code in C, C #, C ++, Python, PL/SQL, Transact SQL, Javascript and Shellscripts on Linux.
- Lately, I've been practicing and exploring the use of AWS cloud tools such as Kubernetes for the creation of containers and the use of Docker for the management of platforms as a service (PaaS) and also the use of Github for the version control and for the work in pipelines in the context of CI/CD.
- I'm very curious about the use of agile cloud tools and I'd be very happy to be on teams that handle these tools.
- I've also gained experience using the stack of tools and software provided in NSK systems such as, Netbatch, SCF, EMS, Inspect and others. I have knowledge in architecture of data replication, problem solving using Oracle Goldengate. I addition, to

solving problems at the scripting level with PL/SQL, DDL and DML in Oracle version 18 and 19 environments.

■ I like technology and I know I don't know everything, but I have the concern to learn everything that helps me to face my own job.

EDUCATION

Fullstack Javascript Developer course in progress at Desafío Latam Academy - Chile Year 2022.

Massachusetts Institute of Technology: Cloud & DevOps Continuous Transformation. Credential: https://www.credential.net/1f91c9cf-9d48-461e-a934-9d45ab1a1b9f#gs.816uww Year 2021.

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering of the University of Santiago de Chile (USACH) Chilean Ministry of Education registration number: Rol 116.806. Year 2015.

Continuing Education Certificate by University Adolfo Ibañez: Negotiation: Quality Campaign. Year 2014.

Continuing Education Certificate by University Adolfo Ibañez: Quality of service. Year 2013.

Continuing Education Certificate by Inmotion: Advanced PL/SQL, "Oracle Database 10g: Advanced PLSQL".

Year 2009.

Systems Analysis by University of Aconcagua. Year 2000 – 2003.

Programming Computer and Systems Analysis by ITESA Institute. Year 1999 – 2000.

Private English tutoring from August 2020 to date, developing speaking skills and constantly working to improve my fluency and pronunciation.